Hello friends, today we will talk
about domestic travel insurance policies. After July 1, 2001, all
domestic travel insurance policies will
become standard. This means that
all insurance companies will have to
introduce domestic travel insurance policies with similar features. Earlier, all
domestic travel insurance policies varied according
to the company. Every
insurance company could
offer more or less features as per its own choice. However,
after the new guidelines of IRDA, the insurance
company will have to keep its domestic policy in a single format. This will make it
much easier for the customer to buy a travel insurance policy.
Earlier, to purchase different policies from each company, the customer had to
study every feature and
check them by visiting different websites.
So let us know
what are the features of this travel policy, what
things will it cover and
how will it help you from a domestic
airport in case of any accident or trouble, so that you
can enjoy your trip if you travel by private
camp, private bus, train, airplane or any other transport.
If you travel,
this policy will cover all these trick tips and this
standard domestic travel insurance
policy has been named Bharat Yatra
Suraksha. Yes, this company will have to
add Bharat Yatra Suraksha with its policy. There are
six basic
mandatory years in this policy, which you will
get invoices from this point onwards. Along with this, there are six
additional options from which you will have to select according to
your requirement and your journey. To
cover all your travel needs, this time this policy has been
divided into parts, which have been
categorized into Plan B, Plan C, Plan D and Plan Z.
Travel up to 100 kilometers by private taxi and bus is covered
in Plan B. If you travel more than 100 kilometers by taxi, cab or bus,
then it is kept in Plan B.
Travel by train is
covered in Plan B, but only for short periods
and there is no distraction of distance in it.
You
can travel as far as you want, this policy covers the entire journey.  The
plan will cover those who travel by plane. Those traveling by plane have been
kept in plan B. There is
no distance restriction in this too. The
last one is plane only. In this plan, you
can travel by any mode of transport, one or
more. There is
no distance restriction in this too. Along with this,
you can travel by private car or aeroplane,
train or even by ship. All modes of travel are
covered in the plan.
Now you must have understood
which plan you have to select according to your journey. The plan of
any travel insurance policy is
from your place of origin to
dropping you at your place of destination. That is
why this journey is covered in all the plans ABCD.
In this plan, the journey
from your place of origin to your return to your place
of origin is
also covered.
Let us know which are the
mandatory benefits that you will
get in these policies. The first is hospitalization
expenses due to accident. The second is
accidental death. The
third is  Permanent Total Disability
Private Limited (PT) The
four 305 and disability for 30 years
Repatriation of Mortal Remains caused by accident
Automatic Trip Extension
We never want you to
need to take any of these good benefits, but
trouble never comes by announcing itself and if there is
something that is most important to us in times of trouble, it is
our insurance policy.
Let us now talk about
what will be your amount limit in these pools. You
can select the limit of Hospital Chennai Express between 1 lakh to 10 lakhs.
Accidental Death Cover can be from 1 lakh to 10 lakhs. You
can click on
Permanent Disability Cover. The cover for accidental will be the same on the cover page. The
cover for permanent disability will also be
accidental on the cover page. The limit for Repatriation of Mortal Remains caused by accident will be
in the middle of the cover. Automatic Trip Extension is
only available in the main menu. You
can know its details in the main menu.
Let us know
what are the optional benefits along with this, first of all  The
company is one of the SEAT clans
Next Flight Connection Third Hello 100%
Check-in baggage 34 strip le
only for travel tours
So then the carrier cancellation is sure
cancellation and interactions
which gave you the validity of the flight
and you will get it in the plan only because
plan D and E cover air travel and
all these official plans are related to air travel only
So friends after watching this video you must have known about the Tendered
Domestic Travel Insurance Policy
Now based on your journey
requirements you
can decide whether you want to
add that NAL cover along with the mandatory cover or
not Our advice is that you should at
least cover the mandatory cover Along with
this we have put the do's and don'ts in the travel policy
in the description You can choose
a better policy for yourself by reading these things in the description
If you liked the video then please do
not forget to like, comment and share Thank you